一提到货运 你脑海中的形象可能包括巨大的集装箱船
When you think of freight transport, the image in your head might include massive container ships
或几英里长的火车 或者巨大的货运飞机
or mile-long trains, or enormous cargo planes,
但比起这些交通工具 承载世界上绝大多数货物的运输方式其实是卡车
but more than each of those, the transportation method
that carries the vast majority of the world's freight is trucks.
在大多数地方 它们甚至承载了美国国内73%的货运量
In most places, it's not even close—by value, they carry 73% of the US' domestic freight.
卡车才是真正把世界连接起来的交通工具
It is truly trucks that connect the world, more than anything else.
它们扮演很多角色 无论是每天为城里的家庭送货
Trucking fills a lot of roles from just daily deliveries to urban households
还是横跨全国把货物从供货商运到消费者手中
all the way to cross-country treks bringing goods from manufacturer to consumer.
然而它的公路长途运输的形式则有很多不为人知的秘密
It is that form, though—long-haul, over-the-road trucking—that is most elusive.
各个国家的高速公路上都能看到这些卡车
These trucks are visible on the highways of any country,
但很多人却没有注意过支撑这个运输系统的基础设施
but the infrastructure supporting this transportation system hides in plain sight.
卡车上路后 长途卡车司机工作外加吃喝拉撒就都在车上进行了
When on the road, long-haul truckers live and work in their trucks.
他们的办公地点显然是驾驶座
Of course their job is centered around sitting behind the wheel,
但驾驶座后面的空间则是他们生活起居的地方
but the section behind that is where they live.
卡车司机只允许每次连续驾驶一定的小时数
Drivers are only allowed to drive a certain number of hours at a time -
在美国是11小时 在欧洲是9小时 世界其他地方也在这俩数附近
in the US, it's 11, in Europe, it's 9, and in the rest of the world it's something similar to those 2.
因此他们在一天不在路上的时候需要有地方休息 起居 重新补给
Therefore, they need the facilities to live, rest,
and recreate when off the road in the remaining hours of the day.
大多数卡车里有一个刚好够大的床 还有电视 微波炉等其他小电器
Most trucks have a cab just large enough for a bed, TV, microwave, and a few other small appliances.
这些设备刻意造得很迷你
They are typically intentionally minimalistic
因为这涉及到驾驶室大小重量和可牵引货物重量之间的权衡
because there is a trade-off between the size and weight of the cab and how much freight can be hauled.
这个权衡多数时候对于司机是很重要的
This truly is a trade-off for the drivers, mostly,
因为在像美国一样的地方 绝大多数司机
as a big proportion of them in places like the US
通常拥有自己的卡车 并以自由职业的身份为公司工作
usually own their truck themselves and work for companies on a freelance basis.
这意味着司机们可以决定买拥有更大更舒适客舱的卡车
That means they could decide to buy a rig with a larger, more comfortable cab,
但后果就是对重型货物运送能力的降低 从而影响收入
but that could make them less capable of hauling heavier loads, which means less money.
卡车限制重量主要是为了保持路况良好
Trucks are weight-restricted mostly to keep the roads in decent condition.
重量越大 对路面影响越大
The greater the weight, the greater the impact.
在美国 这个最大重量因州而异
In the US, this maximum weight varies widely.
多数高速限重36吨(8万磅)
On most highways it's 80,000 pounds or 36,000 kilograms,
不同的州不一样 密歇根的限重高达75吨(16万4千磅)
but this varies from state to state all the way up to 164,000 pounds or 75,000 kilograms in Michigan.
考虑到这种差异 各州的州界主干高速通常会设立称重站
Considering this variance, states will typically have weigh stations near their borders on major highways,
也有一些还会分布在州内
as well as some spread out throughout the state.
所有卡车 除了自带一些电子系统可以直接通过的外
All trucks, except for some that have electric systems allowing them to bypass,
都需要停在一个超大的秤上称重以保证他们没有超过限重
are required to pull off onto massive scales to assure they're complying with the rules.
不过利用这一契机
Using this opportunity, though,
很多称重站使用的技术变得越来越先进 以保证安全合规
many weigh stations have become far more technologically advanced to assure safety and compliance.
比如会使用热成像为车轮拍照 保证刹车运转正常
For example, thermal cameras will take an image of the wheels to assure the brakes are working properly -
如果温度太低 则说明刹车可能根本没启动
if they're too cold, that could mean the brakes are not engaging,
如果温度太高 可能意味着它相比其他刹车部分运转太剧烈
if they're too hot, that could mean they're engaging too much, in comparison to the other brakes.
于是这个重量上的限制导致了大家的卡车大多成了现在的样子：
So, the weight issue, though, is why the average rig looks just like this -
一个勉强能满足司机的舒适体验的拥挤驾驶舱
a compact cab with just the bare minimum of comforts.
这样权衡下来的结果是 加长的睡眠空间一般只适用于比如长途运输的卡车
The trade-off means that larger, extended sleepers are only common with, for example, long-haul moving trucks,
这种卡车运输货物重量不大 很少会有限重的问题
which, due to the low weight and density of the carried goods, rarely have an issue with weight limits.
所以鉴于多数卡车这种只能勉强满足舒适的造型
So, given that most trucks look like this, with just the bare bones of comforts,
卡车司机绝大多数能用上的设施都在他们睡觉的地方——卡车服务区
most of the facilities truckers need are located in the places where they sleep - truck stops.
它们广泛分布在像美国这样大面积的国家
These dot large countries like the US with remarkable frequency,
可见于高速公路和其他卡车运输路线的路边
centered primarily along highways and other common trucking routes.
外表看上去就像一个巨型加油站 但功能远不止加油
They might look like large gas stations, but they offer far more.
卡车客舱里一般没有洗浴室 所以在卡车服务区一般都会有
Truck cabs typically don't have bathrooms or showers, so they almost always have those.
卡车上也不会有洗衣机 所以卡车服务区也会提供洗衣设施
They also don't have laundry facilities, so truck stops often have those.
有些服务区还会有银行 理发师 按摩师 牙医 宠物美容等
Some will also have banks, barbers, chiropractors, dentists, dog groomers, and more.
这一切的原因是 卡车司机一旦上路 就彻底进入这个系统了
This is all because, once truckers are on the road, they're in the system,
在回到出发点之前他们很难离开它
and they can't really leave it until they're back at their origin.
你总不能开着半挂车进城里超市买菜去
One can't just drive into a city and park to do some shopping in a semi-truck,
这不现实 有时还不合法
both practically and, in some cases, legally.
虽然卡车司机一年走过的路几乎比任何人都多
While truckers might travel more miles in a year than anyone else,
但在上路后 高速路和服务区等周边设施就是他们的整个世界
the world, for them, while on the job, is limited to the roads, truck-stops,
and few other facilities catering to them.
所以卡车服务区里有牙医这种事情其实并不新鲜
That's why services like dentists at truck stops are far from novelties.
这些是茫茫公路生涯中的必需
They're crucial fixtures of a life on the road.
卡车司机只有车动起来的时候才能赚钱
Truck drivers only make money when they're moving.
总的来讲 卡车司机是以里程数赚钱的
Overwhelmingly, they are paid per mile
这意味着他们在法律规定的休息时间内是不赚钱的
meaning the time during which they are legally mandatedto rest is unpaid.
不仅如此 实际上在休息时候他们还会赔钱
Not only that, but time off actually loses money.
这件事本质上是一个经济上的计算题
The whole game is an economic puzzle.
卡车停止的时候仍需要动力来运转空调 加热等电器
Trucks need power to run AC, heat, or electronics while stationary -
司机在卡车停下的时候也需要这些
all of which drivers typically need when they're stopped.
因此 司机通常会让车不熄火过夜 每小时会消耗0.8加仑/3升柴油
Therefore, often, drivers leave their trucks idling overnight which burns about 0.8gal or 3L of diesel per hour.
以当前油价 停车10小时会烧掉20美元的柴油
At current prices, a 10-hour overnight stop would burn about $20 of diesel which,
乘上每年每个司机过夜的次数
multiplied by hundreds of nights per year per driver,
就是一笔巨额开销 外加大量的环境负担
is a significant cost and an even greater environmental burden.
另外 空转还会加剧卡车发动机的损耗 影响卡车的保修
In addition, this idling adds wear and tear to the engine, and counts against a truck's warranty.
直到目前 除非你睡觉不开空调 真的没啥解决办法
Until recently, there really wasn't an alternative, except for sleeping without AC or heat,
但在来自环保方面的逐渐增大压力下
but under increased pressure to improve its environmental footprint,
卡车工业开始实施了一些创新 比如辅助动力装置——
the trucking industry has implemented innovations such as auxiliary power units -
一种更小更高效的发电机 在卡车停下后提供电力
smaller, more efficient generators - electric plug-ins at truck stops,
甚至还有安装在车窗上的管道 在停车时可以提供温度控制
or even ducts installed to the windows when stopped to provide climate control.
这个经济上的计算题还会拓展到停车以外的地方
This economic calculation extends beyond stops.
这还要考虑在遵守法律的情况下优化每日最大里程
It also deals with optimizing the miles covered while following the laws.
美国规定14小时内最多可以驾驶11小时
In the US, the rule is that one can drive up to 11 hours, over an overall period of 14 hours,
且之后必须休息10小时
and then must rest for 10 hours.
假设一辆卡车以每小时60英里的速度行驶
Assuming an average speed of 60 miles per hour,
意味着每天可以跑660英里
that means a truck can essentially travel 660 miles per day.
因此从洛杉矶到纽约这种横穿美国的路线要跑四天半
Therefore, a cross-country trip from Los Angeles to New York would take about four and a half days.
卡车司机是按里程结算工钱的
The drivers themselves are paid per mile
所以他们只能在11小时的驾驶时间内最大化行驶速度
so all they want to do is maximize their speed during the 11 hours of daily driving time.
但对于为货柜里的货物花钱的消费者来说
The consumer, though - whoever's paying for the transport of the product in the back -
他们只在乎产品总体上能有多快到达他们手中
cares about how fast it gets to them overall.
因此 卡车司机们发明了一个能让货物跑得更快的办法
Therefore, truckers have devised a system to move freight faster.
法律规定了司机要在客舱里休息10小时
The rules just say that drivers have to rest for ten hours in their cab -
但没规定车必须停下来
it doesn't say that the trucks have to be stationary.
因此 司机们会组队跑运输 一个开车的时候另一个在后面睡觉
Drivers will therefore team up so that while one drives, the other sleeps, and vice versa.
一组司机 通常由一对已婚夫妇组成
A team of drivers, which is often made up of a married couple,
一天能跑22小时 跑1320英里
can therefore drive 22 hours per day, covering 1,320 miles.
这样可以把洛杉矶到纽约的路程缩短到仅两天
That means that they could make the Los Angeles to New York trip in just two days.
客户会为更快的速度付更多的钱 因而卡车公司也会给司机付更高的单价工资
Consumers will pay a premium for the speed, and therefore trucking companies will pay more per mile.
另外 停车时间更短也意味着本就高成本的卡车有更高的运转效率
In addition, having less stopped time means that the truck,
which costs quite a lot, is being used more efficiently.
因此这种组队的方式带来的结果是多赢的
This team system is all-around a win for everyone,
前提是我们能找到互相能容忍在卡车上过日子的那个ta
assuming one can find a pair of people that will tolerate spending their lives cooped up in a truck cab together.
不过 几乎可以肯定的是 卡车司机也快变成夕阳职业了
Truckers, almost certainly, are a dying breed, though.
货运的未来毫无疑问会围绕着自动驾驶卡车
The future of freight transport will undoubtably center around self-driving trucks
而相关技术也在飞速蓬勃发展
and the technology for these is very close to ready for prime-time.
现在 多家公司的卡车已经具备了自动驾驶的能力
Right now, multiple companies are at the point where their trucks are traveling autonomously,
卡车司机只要在需要时介入操控即可
with drivers behind the wheel to intervene if needed.
这些大体上都是类似特斯拉的自动驾驶系统 帮助减少司机的疲劳状况
These are essentially autopilot systems, similar to Tesla's, that aid the driver and reduce fatigue.
而很快 有了更成熟的技术与完善的法规后
Soon, though, with more proven technology and legal authority to do so,
公路运输很可能会发展成自动驾驶车队
this will likely advance to autonomous convoys.
在该系统中 卡车司机只坐在领头的卡车里
In this system, one driver would sit behind the wheel of a lead truck,
该车可能也是处于自动驾驶状态
which might also drive autonomously,
后面紧跟着几辆无人驾驶卡车
and then a series of autonomous, human-less trucks would follow behind.
这样 仍然保证有一个人可以应付机械问题或不可预知的路况
This way, there is still a human that can assist with mechanical issues or unforeseen road conditions,
但卡车与司机的人数比会极大增加
but the freight to driver ratio increases dramatically.
显然这也会极大降低卡车司机的需求量
This will, of course, reduce the number of truckers needed,
但在这个阶段过后 该行业无疑将推进到全自动驾驶卡车的阶段
but then, after this phase, the industry will undoubtably advance to fully autonomous trucks.
最初可能只跑固定路线
At first, this will likely just be on dedicated routes -
比如一家公司可能会在两个仓库之间不复杂的路段上部署这些无人卡车
for example, a company might deploy these on uncomplicated routes from one warehouse to another,
两个仓库离高速都很近
both being close to a highway.
在高速上的自动驾驶相对简单 因为路面都是标准化的 相对更可预测
Autonomous driving on highways is relatively easy since roads conditions are standardized and predictable.
城市内的自动驾驶则更加复杂一些
Autonomous city driving is much more complicated,
所以人类司机可能在路程的首尾阶段仍然需要参与进来
so human drivers might still be needed for the start and end of journeys.
不过全自动驾驶能做到的是
What fully autonomous driving could do, though,
卡车在高速上行驶的时候让司机在后面休息
is allow a truck to continue moving on the highway while a driver rests in the back,
从而打破工作时间上的限制 实现连续不间断行驶
allowing essentially continuous driving without having to deal with working hour limits.
再结合车队系统 卡车的运输效率将会极大提高
This, along with a convoy system, could increase the cost efficiency of trucking dramatically,
因为人类司机的人力成本也是个大头
as the human drivers represent a significant cost.
平均每英里要付卡车司机35美分
An average trucker's pay is about 35 cents per mile,
因此削减这部分的成本后 洛杉矶到纽约的运输将会减少将近1000美元的成本
meaning that cutting out that cost entirely would reduce the cost of a Los Angeles to New York trip,
for example, by almost $1,000.
这也是为什么会有这么多公司会在自动驾驶卡车上下功夫
It is for this reason why so many companies are pursuing autonomous trucks.
当然 卡车运输的另一个成本是燃料
Of course, the other major cost in trucking is fuel,
所以各公司也都在这方面进行创新
so companies are also trying to innovate in that space.
在部署自动驾驶卡车的同时可能会转型使用电动卡车
Concurrent to the deployment of autonomous trucks is a likely shift into the use of electric trucks.
比如特斯拉就在研发自己的半挂卡车
Tesla, for example, is developing its own semi truck.
特斯拉宣称能耗约为每英里2千瓦时
They claim its energy consumption will be about two kilowatt hours per mile.
美国平均电价每千瓦时10美分
The US' average energy cost is about 10 cents per kilowatt hour,
换算过来就是每英里20美分
which translates to an energy cost of about 20 cents per mile.
传统内燃机半挂卡车每加仑燃料能跑6英里
Typical internal combustion semi-trucks have an efficiency of about 6 miles per gallon,
以当前油价 换算过来每英里要40美分
so, at current diesel prices, that would translate to a cost of about 40 cents per mile.
让卡车公司的能源价格减半 绝对是一个吸引人的点子
Halving a trucking company's energy prices is certainly an intriguing proposition,
因此很多人看好特斯拉的半挂卡车前景
which is why many consider the Tesla semi so promising.
按照以上计算的价格 如果让卡车全自动无人驾驶 省去人力成本
At those prices, if a truck goes driverless, meaning no salary costs,
像洛杉矶到纽约这种横穿美国的运输成本可能降低到只有550美元
the variable cost of a cross-country, Los Angeles to New York run would be just $550.
如果只用几百美元就能在美国千家万户之间运输数十吨的货物
To be able to haul tens of thousands of pounds of goods from door to door across the country
那这必将导致货运系统翻天覆地的变化
for just hundreds of dollars would result in a paradigm shift in the freight world.
当然这里面还会有别的问题 比如电池组的重量会拖累卡车整体运力
There are certainly disadvantages, such as the high battery pack weight that reduces cargo capacity,
但毫无疑问的是 在不久的未来电动卡车一定会在卡车行业内发挥作用
but it is clear that electric trucks will play some role in the industry regardless in the near future.
这种作用可能会集中在短途路线而不是长途路线上
This role will likely be concentrated in shorter routes, rather than long-haul ones,
但这也已经是一个足够值得重视的行业分支了
but this is still a significant enough subset of the industry
因为电动卡车可能为此带来翻天覆地的变化
that electric trucks have the potential for significant disruption.
现在这种对立的现象很奇怪 卡车司机对现代世界经济的贡献如此重要
Right now, there is an strange duality where truckers are so crucial the running of a modern economy
但全世界都在考虑如何用机器取代他们
that the world is working to replace them.
我们现在还不能没有他们 但我们正在想办法
We can't live without them right now, so we're finding a way to.
但在未来
In the future, though,
卡车司机的工作无疑将成为日益现代化的世界的另一个受害者
the job of a trucker will undoubtably be another victim of an increasingly modernized world.